Min (Mia) Shi

Dallas, TX 75252 | (469) 403-7557 | minmiashi@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/min-mia-shi/

SUMMARY

Dedicated Business Analytics and Data Analytics masters' student with two years of work experience in data analysis and database management; Equipped with strong skills in data visualization, SQL query, big data, machine learning (ML) and time series model building; Actively seeking 2023 summer intern in Data Analyst/Data Science.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Candidate in Political ScienceAnticipated May 2024The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TXGPA: 3.924/4.0Master of Science in Social Data Analytics and ResearchAnticipated May 2024The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TXGPA: 3.924/4.0Master of Science in Business AnalyticsAnticipated May 2024The University of Texas at Dallas, Richardson, TXGPA: 4.0/4.0

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: Python, R, SQL, Stata

Tools: Alteryx, Tableau, Jupyter Notebook, Excel Charts, R Shiny

Database & Big Data: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Mango DB, Amazon RDS, Hadoop, Sqoop, Hive, Impala, Pig, Spark

Certificate: Graduate Certificate in Applied Machine Learning at UTD

Languages: English, Chinese, Japanese

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant - School of Economic, Political & Policy Sciences at UTD

May 2020 - August 2022

- Accomplished data cleaning of 1212 cross-country surveys in Python, utilized ML models decision-tree, support vector machine to perform data analysis in R, leading to an increase in prediction accuracy by 80 %
- Generated an original database of 13 tables containing stock data for S&P 500 companies, GDP data for over 200 countries, and U.S.-China trade-related data which improves the extraction efficiency by 3 times
- Performed visualization in Python, adopted time series GARCH models in modeling the effects of U.S.-China trade conflicts on U.S. companies, with an increase of 20% in accuracy compared to other regression models
- Presented the findings at 2022 International Society for Data Science and Analytics Conference

Database Management Intern – Lucion Technology Corp., Ltd., China

July 2017 - August 2017

- Collaborated with IT department manager and used MySQL to manage enterprise users' information, orders of services, billing, and the deployed network devices data, which improved data extraction efficiency by 50%
- Visualized network structures of Lucion Tech. Corp. in Microsoft Visio
- Created over ten BI reports based on analysis of users' structure, competitors, and market trend

PROJECTS

Geospatial Truck Fleet Big Data Analytics and Visualization

August 2022 – November 2022

- Used big data Hadoop ecosystem to process geospatial data ingestion, transformation, and database creation
- Performed data exploration and visualization in Tableau by connecting to Hadoop ecosystem server
- Modeled how factors affect the truck driver risk factor, drew a final report and proposed suggestions on how to lower the probability of large trucks accidents

Payroll Management System Database Design via MySQL

June 2022 – August 2022

- Led a group of five in conducting business requirements analysis and designing a payroll management database with MySQL consisting of 13 tables
- Increased efficiency in extract-transform-load and payroll database management by 100% via stored functions, procedures, and triggers

COVID-19 Worldwide Cases Synchronous Dashboard using Tableau

December 2021 – January 2022

- Designed a synchronous Tableau dashboard with advanced interactive functions to explore COVID-19 severity
- Utilized Tableau to probe the correlation between factors and the severity of COVID-19 by country

AWARDS